Finding Aid for the Stuart Wright Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Stuart Wright Collection
1896-1988
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0533
.63 linear feet
Biography/History
Stuart Wright of Winston-Salem, North Carolina was on the faculty of the School of Education at Wake Forest University. He was the owner/publisher of Palaemon Press Limited, a private press that published books, pamphlets, and broadsides by, Southern authors. He was a bibliographer and collector of southern literature especially for Fugitive/Agrarian authors and their associates. This collection relates primarily to Robert Penn Warren.
Scope and Contents
The .63 linear feet collection (2 boxes) contains correspondence between Robert Penn Warren and George Core, as well as correspondence between Robert Penn Warren and Stuart Wright. There is also correspondence from Eleanor Clark to Stuart Wright. Many of the letters refer to the publishing of books, but many are personal in nature. Some of the letters are typed and some handwritten. The collection is arranged into two series, in two boxes: Series I contains 232 pieces of correspondence, eight poems, four report cards of Robert Penn Warren, and 21 envelopes; Series II contains 131 photographs (mostly of Robert Penn Warren), and 2 contact sheets with 44 images. The folders are arranged by subject and chronologically within the collection.
- Series I
  - Correspondence – Robert Penn Warren to George Core 35 letters/postcards, 8 poems
    - September 9, 1970 (Box 1)
    - May 8, 1975 (Box 1)
    - August 3, 1975 (Box 1)
    - August 16, 1975 (Box 1)
    - November 16, 1975 (Box 1)
    - March 23, 1976 (Box 1)
    - October 8, 1976 (Box 1)
    - October 21, 1976 (Box 1)
    - November 8, 1976 (Box 1)
    - June 20, 1977 (Box 1)
    - September 9, 1977 (Box 1)
    - August 12, 1980 (Box 1)
    - October 16, 1980 – postcard (Box 1)
    - November 17, 1980 (Box 1)
    - December 18, 1980 (Box 1)
    - January 3, 1981 (Box 1)
    - May 12, 1981 w/poem (Box 1)
      Convergences by Robert Penn Warren
    - August 14, 1981 – postcard (Box 1)
    - September 11, 1981 – postcard (Box 1)
    - December 18, 1981 – postcard (Box 1)
    - June 16, 1982 (Box 1)
    - June 30, 1982 (Box 1)
    - September 7, 1982 (Box 1)
    - January 24, 1983 w/poems (Box 1)
      Personal History, by Robert Penn Warren
      Mortal Limit, by Robert Penn Warren
      Delusion?-No!, by Robert Penn Warren
      Why You Climbed Up, by Robert Penn Warren
      Problem of Autobiography, by Robert Penn Warren
      Argument For Prayer, by Robert Penn Warren
    - March 30, 1983 (Box 1)
    - August 8, 1983 (Box 1)
    - September 27, 1983 w/poem (Box 1)
      Tulip-Tree In Bloom by Robert Penn Warren
    - October 11, 1983 (Box 1)
    - October 19, 1983 (Box 1)
    - October 31, 1983 – postcard (Box 1)
    - March 31, 1984 (Box 1)
    - April 2, 1984 (Box 1)
    - October 10, 1984 (Box 1)
    - November 26, 1984 (Box 1)
    - December 2, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence – George Core to Robert Penn Warren 19 letters
    - January 7, 1980 (Box 1)
    - August 5, 1980 (Box 1)
    - August 19, 1980 (Box 1)
    - September 29, 1980 (Box 1)
    - December 10, 1980 (Box 1)
    - February 13, 1981 (Box 1)
    - May 1, 1981 (Box 1)
    - May 1, 1981 (Box 1)
    - May 17, 1981 (Box 1)
    - June 22, 1982 (Box 1)
    - July 10, 1982 (Box 1)
    - September 26, 1982 (Box 1)
    - January 30, 1983 (Box 1)
    - March 16, 1983 (Box 1)
    - April 4, 1983 (Box 1)
    - October 5, 1983 (Box 1)
    - October 20, 1983 (Box 1)
    - April 5, 1984 (Box 1)
    - April 18, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence – Robert Penn Warren to Stuart Wright 140 letters/postcards
    - September 2, 1977 (Box 1)
    - October 2, 1977 (Box 1)
    - October 14, 1977 - postcard (Box 1)
    - January 28, 1978 (Box 1)
    - February 1, 1978 – postcard (Box 1)
    - February 2, 1978 (Box 1)
    - February 24, 1978 (Box 1)
    - March 2, 1978 - postcard (Box 1)
    - March 18, 1978 – postcard (Box 1)
    - April 3, 1978 (Box 1)
    - April 22, 1978 (Box 1)
    - May 21, 1978 (Box 1)
    - June 8, 1978 - postcard (Box 1)
    - June 14, 1978 – postcard (Box 1)
    - June 26, 1978 (Box 1)
    - June 27, 1978 (Box 1)
    - August 14, 1978 (Box 1)
    - September 15, 1978 (Box 1)
    - December 6, 1978 – postcard (Box 1)
    - December 14, 1978 – postcard (Box 1)
    - March 4, 1979 – postcard (Box 1)
    - April 24, 1979 – postcard (Box 1)
    - May 4, 1979 (Box 1)
    - May 18, 1979 – postcard (Box 1)
    - May 28, 1979 (Box 1)
    - June 5, 1979 – postcard (Box 1)
    - June 5, 1979 (Box 1)
    - July 17, 1979 (Box 1)
    - September 13, 1979 – postcard (Box 1)
    - September 28, 1979 - postcard (Box 1)
    - October 30, 1979 (Box 1)
    - November 8, 1979 (Box 1)
    - 1980 – postcard (Box 1)
    - 1980 – postcard (Box 1)
    - February 1, 1980 – postcard (Box 1)
    - March 11, 1980 – postcard (Box 1)
    - June 11, 1980 – postcard (Box 1)
    - July 7, 1980 - postcard (Box 1)
    - September 8, 1980 (Box 1)
    - October 18, 1980 (Box 1)
    - October 19, 1980 – postcard #1 (Box 1)
    - October 19, 1980 – postcard #2 (Box 1)
    - December 12, 1980 (Box 1)
    - December 17, 1980 – postcard (Box 1)
    - January 28, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 1, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 3, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 6, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 9, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 9, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 13, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 19, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 19, 1981 (Box 1)
    - March 2, 1981 (Box 1)
    - March 9, 1981 – postcard #1 (Box 1)
    - March 9, 1981 – postcard #2 (Box 1)
    - May 12, 1981 (Box 1)
    - June 1, 1981 (Box 1)
    - June 7, 1981 (Box 1)
    - June 12, 1981 (Box 1)
    - June 22, 1981 – postcard (Box 1)
    - July 1, 1981 (Box 1)
    - July 20, 1981 (Box 1)
    - September 1, 1981 (Box 1)
    - September 11, 1981 (Box 1)
    - February 11, 1982 (Box 1)
    - March 5, 1982 (Box 1)
    - March 22, 1982 (Box 1)
    - July 23, 1982 (Box 1)
    - July 19, 1982 (Box 1)
    - September 14, 1982 (Box 1)
    - November 4, 1982 (Box 1)
    - November 22, 1982 (Box 1)
    - January 22, 1983 (Box 1)
    - February 1, 1983 – postcard (Box 1)
    - February 4, 1983 – postcard (Box 1)
    - May 25, 1983 (Box 1)
    - June 4, 1983 (Box 1)
    - October 5, 1983 (Box 1)
    - October 6, 1983 (Box 1)
    - October 20, 1983 – postcard (Box 1)
    - January 19, 1984 (Box 1)
    - January 21, 1984 (Box 1)
    - February 20, 1984 (Box 1)
    - February 26, 1984 (Box 1)
    - March 15, 1984 (Box 1)
    - June 11, 1984 (Box 1)
    - August 10, 1984 (Box 1)
    - April 11, 1985 (Box 1)
    - June 7, 1985 (Box 1)
    - June 17, 1985 (Box 1)
    - June 23, 1985 (Box 1)
    - September 7, 1985 (Box 1)
    - September 8, 1985 (Box 1)
    - January 15, 1986 (Box 1)
    - January 29, 1986 (Box 1)
    - January 23, 1987 (Box 1)
    - February 5, 1987 (Box 1)
    - February 28, 1987 (Box 1)
    - February 28, 1987 (Box 1)
    - March 4, 1987 (Box 1)
    - March 5, 1987 (Box 1)
    - March 9, 1987 (Box 1)
    - March 20, 1987 (Box 1)
    - June 8, 1987 (Box 1)
    - June 13, 1987 (Box 1)
    - June 15, 1987 (Box 1)
    - June 16, 1987 (Box 1)
    - June 16, 1987 (Box 1)
    - June 19, 1987 (Box 1)
    - June 28, 1987 (Box 1)
    - June 30, 1987 (Box 1)
    - July 16, 1987 (Box 1)
    - July 16, 1987 (Box 1)
    - July 27, 1987 (Box 1)
    - August 15, 1987 (Box 1)
    - August 25, 1987 (Box 1)
    - August 26, 1987 (Box 1)
    - August 27, 1987 (Box 1)
    - August 29, 1987 (Box 1)
    - August 29, 1987 (Box 1)
    - September 11, 1987 (Box 1)
    - September 17, 1987 (Box 1)
    - October 3, 1987 (Box 1)
    - October 3, 1987 (Box 1)
    - October 7, 1987 (Box 1)
    - October 7, 1987 (Box 1)
    - October 13, 1987 (Box 1)
    - October 21, 1987 (Box 1)
    - November 1987 (Box 1)
    - October 5, 1987 (Box 1)
    - November 7, 1987 (Box 1)
    - November 16, 1987 (Box 1)
    - November 18, 1987 (Box 1)
    - November 20, 1987 (Box 1)
    - November 30, 1987 (Box 1)
    - December 26, 1987 (Box 1)
    - February 9, 1988 (Box 1)
    - March 18, 1988 (Box 1)
    - March 25, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence – Eleanor Clark to Stuart Wright 38 letters/postcards
    - August 14, 1978 (Box 1)
    - June 23, 1979 (Box 1)
    - January 12, 1980 - postcard (Box 1)
    - March 18, 1980 (Box 1)
    - August 20, 1981 – postcard (Box 1)
    - January 24, 1984 (Box 1)
    - March 9, 1984 (Box 1)
    - April 25, 1984 (Box 1)
    - May 25, 1984 (Box 1)
    - June 13, 1984 – postcard (Box 1)
    - June 26, 1984 (Box 1)
    - September 4, 1984 (Box 1)
    - October 1, 1984 (Box 1)
    - October 10, 1984 (Box 1)
    - October 15, 1984 (Box 1)
    - October 21, 1984 – postcard (Box 1)
    - October 28, 1984 (Box 1)
    - November 2, 1984 (Box 1)
    - November 9, 1984 (Box 1)
    - November 27, 1984 (Box 1)
    - December 13, 1984 (Box 1)
    - December 27, 1984 – postcard (Box 1)
    - January 2, 1985 (Box 1)
    - January 6, 1985 (Box 1)
    - January 16, 1985 (Box 1)
    - April 5, 1985 (Box 1)
    - April 30, 1985 (Box 1)
    - May 6, 1985 - postcard (Box 1)
    - May 29, 1985 - postcard (Box 1)
    - June 7, 1985 (Box 1)
    - June 30, 1985 (Box 1)
    - September 17, 1985 (Box 1)
    - December 29, 1986 (Box 1)
    - January 9, 1987 – postcard (Box 1)
    - January 30, 1987 (Box 1)
    - September 14, 1987 – postcard (Box 1)
    - September 6, 1988 – postcard (Box 1)
    - n.d. (Box 1)
  - Report Cards – Robert Penn Warren – (4)
    - 1913-1914 (Box 1)
    - 1914-1915 (Box 1)
    - 1918-1919 (Box 1)
    - 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - Envelopes – (21)
- Series II
  - Photographs
    - Robert Penn Warren (Box 1)
    - Mrs. R. F. Warren (mother)– 1896 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Franklin Warren (father)- 1898 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren, as an infant with his parents – 1905 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – [1906] – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – 1908 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – 1912 - (2) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – 1919 - (2) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – 1920 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – 1925 (Vanderbilt Senior) – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – November 1942 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – mid-1940s outside Scribners – (20) 3 ¾ x 4 ½ and (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – 1945 – (8) 4 x 6 and (1) 7 ½ x 8 (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – 1946-47 – (3) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren at Swanee – November 1974 – (1) 8x10 (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren and Emma ‘Cinina’ Brescia (1st wife) – [1948] – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren and Eleanor Clark (2nd wife) – [1948] – (4) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Taormina – from Window of Salotto – 1948 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – August 1949 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – at Yale – [1940s] – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren w/Thomas Berger and Quasimodo – [1950s] – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren w/Eleanor Clark and Daughter Rosanna – [1956] – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – May 8, 1959 – (5) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren at Oxford, Mississippi – April 24, 1965 – (1) - color (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – in Japan – [1960s] – (4) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren, receiving award from President Carter – June 9, 1980 (1) 8x10, color (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – 1982 – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – [1950s] – (2) 7 ½ x 9 ¼ (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – [1950s] - (11) 8x10 (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – [1970s] – (7) w/one color (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren – [1980s] – (8) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren, at unidentified event – n.d. – (1) (Box 1)
    - Robert Penn Warren, at unidentified event – n.d. - (8) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Agrarian Reunion (Box 1)
      1980 – (1)
    - Fugitive Reunion (Box 1)
      May 5, 1956 – (3)
    - Fugitive Reunion Dinner (Box 1)
      1956 – (1)
    - Poetry Festival (Box 1)
      1961 – (2)
    - Brother to Dragons – Production Photographs (Box 1)
      1968 – (5)
    - Robert Penn Warren and Director Adrian Hall – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Ronald Frazier and William Cain as Ishom and Lilburn Lewis – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - William Cain as Lilburn Lewis and Marguerite Lenert as Lucy Lewis – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Richard Kneeland as Thomas Jefferson – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Richard Kneeland as Thomas Jefferson, Marguerite Lenert as Lucy Lewis, William Cain as Lilburn Lewis – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Eleanor Clark (Box 1)
      Receiving award for Robert Penn Warren
      [1980s] – (1)
    - Denis Devlin (Box 1)
      (1) - 8 x 10, black and white, etching
      (1) - 7 x 9 ¼, black and white, portrait – 1955
    - Randall Jarrell (Box 1)
      [1961] – (1)
    - Alberto Moravia (Box 1)
      [1950s] – (1)
    - Katherine Anne Porter – University of Maryland (Box 1)
    - Plaque for Katherine Anne Porter Room at the University of Maryland – May 15, 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Katherine Anne Porter with bouquet of flowers – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Katherine Anne Porter seated on stage w/participants – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Katherine Anne Porter being escorted around room – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - Visitors to Katherine Anne Porter Room – 1968 – (1) 8 x 10 (Box 1)
    - John Crowe Ransom (Box 1)
      [1947] – (1)
    - Unidentified - Individuals (Box 1)
      n.d. – (4)
    - Contact Sheets (Box 1)
      [1980s] – (2) – 44 images
    - Negatives (Box 1)